Ismael Espindola

Web Developer and Visual Designer

I am looking for my first IT job. I have been improving my skills as a web developer for more than two years, and I have more than 15 years as a graphic designer. I want to be able to contribute my experience and skills in innovative and challenging projects, being part of first-class work teams.

| Contact | Relevant coursework | |
|------------------------------------------|-------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------|-----------|
| La Rioja, Argentina +54 9 380 4646916 | Node.js: Essential LinkedIn Learning, backend web development | Oct. 2020 |
| EspiFreelancer.com | Node.js: Practical LinkedIn Learning, backend web development | Nov. 2020 |
| twitter.com/ EspiFreelancer | JavaScript: Essential LinkedIn Learning, full-stack web developer | Aug. 2020 |
| github.com/ EspiFreelancer | JavaScript: Advanced - Regular Expressions LinkedIn Learning, full-stack web developer | Aug. 2020 |
| in linkedin.com/in/ | JavaScript: Advanced - Best Practices LinkedIn Learning, full-stack web developer | Aug. 2020 |
| EspiFreelancer | SQL: Essential LinkedIn Learning, backend web development | Oct. 2020 |
| Skill | Learn relational database design LinkedIn Learning, backend web development | Oct. 2020 |
| Python | Amazon Web Services Practitioners Ministry of Planning and Industry, backend web development | Jul. 2019 |
| JavaScript Django | Web development: Automated quality control LinkedIn Learning, software development skills | Oct. 2020 |
| PostgreSQL | Introduction to Software Testing National University of La Rioja (UNLAR), software development skills | Oct. 2019 |
| MySQL/MariaDB | GitHub for developers LinkedIn Learning, full-stack web developer | Nov. 2020 |
| IBM/Watson | Learn SCRUM LinkedIn Learning, software development skills | Aug. 2020 |
| Testing | Scrum: Roles LinkedIn Learning, software development skills | Aug. 2020 |
| | Teamwork LinkedIn Learning, software development skills | Nov. 2020 |
| | Events and competitions | |
| | Mayatana Bahind the Code 2020 IBM Latin America | A |

Maratona Behind the Code 2020 | IBM Latin America

Aug./Sep. 2020

Eight real company business challenges in five weeks. Using:

- Watson Assistant
- Watson Knowkedge Studio
- Watson Natural Language Understanding
- Watson Machine Learning
- Machine Learning (with Jupyter Notebooks)
- Feature engineering

Courses without certificate

| Python pildorasinformaticas, POO | Jul. 2017 |
|---------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------|-------------|
| Django mozilla.org - developers, backend web development | Dec. 2017 |
| Django REST codigofacilito, backend web development | Oct. 2019 |
| PostgreSQL Tecnología Binaria, backend web development | Aug. 2019 |
| Vue.js 2 Bluuweb, frontend web development | Jan. 2020 |
| Git makigas, practical software development skills | Feb. 2019 |
| Education | |
| National University of La Rioja (UNLAR), Argentina Industrial engineering (three years, unfinished career) | 2001 - 2004 |
| Professional Experience | |
| Graphic designer, Chimichanga | 2014 - 2019 |

Own entrepreneurship with partner.

- Adaptation of images for printing on clothing.
 - · Photo retouching.
 - Logo creation, event packaging, brochures, etc
 - Preparation of jobs for printing on different media.
 - Color separation for screen printing, image preparation for cutting plotter.
- Traditional and digital illustration.

Graphic designer, Telestar

2003 - 2018

Service provider.

- Technical maintenance of computer equipment, networks, printers and photocopiers.
- Multiple equipment printing management.
- Preparing documents for printing.
- Creation of posters, brochures, photo retouching, video editing.

Radiophonic technical operator, National University of La Rioja (UNLAR)

2002 - 2003

Live equipment operation. Editing and post-production.

- Radio broadcast programming (Automatic Satellite Connection, entry of programmed advertising guidelines, opening / closing of radio programs and content for re-broadcast, independent musical content of the program).
- Technical maintenance and repair of equipment.
- Active participation in production teams.
- Performance as an assistant sound engineer.

This CV is online and always updated at: EspiFreelancer.github.io